<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.3//EN"
                 "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.3/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % sharedents SYSTEM "shared-entities.xml" >
%sharedents;
]>
<book id="salt ceph roadmapBook" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">

  <title>salt ceph road map</title>
  <subtitle>2014-01-21</subtitle>
  <titleabbrev>salt ceph road map</titleabbrev>

  <bookinfo>
    <abstract>
      <para>This is the planning document for salt integration of ceph. It 
      intends to cover use cases requirements and specification, and design ideas
      allowing us to keep out understanding of what our project has achieved and 
      what is still to be done clear and unambiguous.
      </para>
    </abstract>

    <date>2016-06-06</date>
    <author>
      <firstname>Owen</firstname>
      <surname>Synge</surname>
    </author>
  </bookinfo>

  <preface id="preface">
    <title>Preface</title>
    <para>salt is a configuration management system with a toolkit for cluster 
    software.
    </para>
    <section id="observations">
      <title>ceph salt Observations</title>
      <para>salt is a large tool kit and its easy to become overwhelmed by 
      possibilities offered by salt to the user.</para>
      
      <para>I believe the process of design should be based upon:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>Use cases</listitem>
        <listitem>Requirements</listitem>
        <listitem>Specifications</listitem>
        <listitem>Design</listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <section id="preface_usecase">
        <title>Use cases</title>
        <para>Who and what is meant to be achieved</para>
      </section>
      <section id="preface_requirements">
        <title>Requirements</title>
        <para>What we should be doing derived from use cases</para>
      </section>
      <section id="preface_specifications">
        <title>Specifications</title>
        <para>What we will be doing derived from requirements</para>
      </section>
      <section id="preface_design">
        <title>Design</title>
        <para>How we do it derived from specifications.</para>
      </section>
      <para>This formality will help us understand what and why we are doing things, 
      and allow management to track our progress.</para>
      <para>As the documentation matures I would relax the derivation rules such that 
      use cases can reference components that have been added to design, but to facilitate 
      large sprints we can relax it further to components added to the specifications.</para>
      <para>For example if we had a use case to configure a "rbd service" we have dependencies 
      on things that have been placed in the specification about "dependency management."</para>
      <para>as a living document I suggest moving this into doc book on gitlab.</para>
      <para>This will allow us to use code review techniques to allow change control.</para>
      <para>This will allow us to have an ongoing mechanism to add fate requests to the 
      use cases, specifications.</para>
    </section>
  </preface>
  <toc/>
  <xi:include href="chapter_actors.xml"/>
  <xi:include href="chapter_usecases.xml"/>
  <xi:include href="chapter_requirements.xml"/>
  <xi:include href="chapter_specifications.xml"/>
  <xi:include href="chapter_design.xml"/>
</book>

